Guide to the Brooklyn photograph and illustration collection ARC.202
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Images by Subject
  - Street Scenes and Buildings (Box 19, Folder 19)
    Streets include Clinton Avenue, Snyder Avenue (1910, home of Mr. and Mrs. Christopher Shafer, gift of Peter Blulim, 1996); Elton Street; Fulton Street; Flatbush Avenue; corner of Joralemon Street and Court Street; Marlborough Road.
  - Sunset Park (Box 20, Folder 1)
    One image of 4th Avenue at 51st Street (1902) and one image of a home at the foot of 39th Street.
  - Transportation - Buses (Box 20, Folder 2)
    One image of what appears to be a dispatcher.
  - Transportation - Cars (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Transportation - Destruction of the Myrtle Avenue elevated railroad, 1970-1971 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    Gift of Adelay Liss, executrix of Robert Kahn's estate.
  - Transportation - Elevated Trains, Queens (Box 20, Folder 5)
    Gift of Theodore B. Wiebel, 1973.
  - Transportation - Ferryboats (Box 20, Folder 6)
    Many images of Fulton Ferry.
  - Transportation - Horses (Box 20, Folder 7)
    Includes a color illustration of a horse-drawn railroad car (gift of H.M. Nicholson); photograph of S. Sylvester May Gas and Electric fixtures horse-drawn vehicle, Schermerhorn Street, c. 1905; black and white illustrations of sleighing parties; and a photograph of Frank Waring and others in a horse-drawn carriage (gift of Thomas Ahern, 1993).
    There is an additional photograph of Frank Waring filed under Business and Commerce - Business.
  - Transportation - LIRR (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Transportation - NY Transit Strike, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Transportation - Railroads (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Transportation - Trolleys (Box 25)
  - Washington Centennial, 1889 April 30 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    Many of the photos in this folder were the gift of E.P. Luquer.
  - Waterfronts (Box 20, Folder 12)
    Includes a set of captioned photographs of an aerial inspection of the Atlantic shore front from Staten Island to Montauk, 1962. Several photos labeled "Schwartz collection."
  - Weeksville (Box 20, Folder 13)
    Includes a set of reproductions of drawings made from photographs found at Weeksville. The reproductions are (c) 1973, Society for the Preservation of Weeksville and Bedford Stuyvesant History, and include an explanatory text.
  - West Indian Americans (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Williamsburg (Box 20, Folder 15)
    One color illustration of ice skaters on Union Pond and three images related to Morrison V.R. Weyant's 1926 book "The fountain at Bedford Avenue and Division Avenue, Brooklyn, 1859."
  - World War I, Underwood & Underwood (Box 20, Folder 16)
    Many if not all of these photos are not of Brooklyn.
  - World War II (Box 20, Folder 17)
    Includes a photograph by Nick L. Senzamici of Brooklyn, gift of Ralph R. Colantuoni, depicting a service flag dedication on Somers Street between Rockaway Avenue and Stone, April 1942.